Guide to the Jay Carr Papers 1905-1919
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Jay Carr Papers
1905-1919
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 567
Carr, Jay
0.5 linear feet 1 box
Jay Carr was a businessman in Taft, Montana; Hamilton, Montana; and Ronan, Montana. The collection contains records relating to his various businesses, especially Carr & Peck of Ronan, Montana; and personal papers, including correspondence, a diary, and photographs.
Biographical Note
Jay Carr came from northern Idaho to the railroad town of Taft, Montana, in August 1907 and entered the restaurant business there. Shortly after, he started a saloon in association with that restaurant, and in 1909 sold the saloon to Earl V. Peck, who was to become a longtime business partner. In July 1909 the restaurant was closed, and Carr prospected and worked in saloons and cafes in western Montana and northern Idaho. In 1910, he settled in Hamilton, Montana, and in 1911, he and Peck opened the Pure Food Cafe there. In 1912, the cafe closed, and Carr and Peck moved to Ronan where they operated the freighting and contracting firm of Carr & Peck, which soon branched into the logging business. In 1918, Carr left Ronan and moved to Tarkio. He was married to Alice F. Carr.
The collection contains records relating to his various businesses, especially Carr & Peck of Ronan, Montana; and personal papers, including correspondence and a diary. The Carr & Peck materials include financial and legal agreements, correspondence with suppliers, and financial records that include customer names in Ronan. Personal materials include personal letters between Carr and family members, his diary from 1905 to 1915, and his personal impressions of Taft, Montana. Photographs include images of Taft, Hamilton, the Bitterroot Valley, and Elkhorn, Montana.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
Gift of A.M. Sterling family, date unknown.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Peck, Earl V.
Carr & Peck
Bitterroot River Valley (Mont.)--Photographs; Elkhorn (Jefferson County, Mont.) -- Photographs; Hamilton (Ravalli County, Mont.)--Photographs; Ronan (Mont.); Taft (Mont.)--History; Taft (Mont.)--Photographs
Bars (Drinking establishments)--Montana--Taft; Business Enterprises -- Montana--Ronan; Freight and freightage -- Montana--Ronan
Logging--Montana -- Ronan; Restaurants--Montana -- Hamilton (Ravalli County); Business records -- Montana; Diaries -- Montana; Photographs -- Montana
Montana
Businessmen -- Montana
- Correspondence, 1908-1919 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Carr and Peck, Accounts receivable ledger, 1913-1916 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Carr and Peck order book, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Carr and Peck, financial and legal, 1911-1917 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Financial and legal, 1907-1915 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Diary, 1905-1915 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Description of Taft, Montana, undated (Box-folder 1/7)
- Map of St. Joe River, Idaho, undated (Box-folder 1/8)
- Printed materials and bookmark, undated (Box-folder 1/9)
- Photographs (Box-folder 1/10)
- Winter view of a street in Taft, Montana, ca. 1910; 72-0001 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Winter view of Elkhorn, Montana, with Elkhorn Mill, ca. 1913; 72-0002 (Box-folder 1/10)
- View of the Bitterroot Valley, showing irrigation ditch, near Hamilton, Montana, ca. 1910; 72-0003 (Box-folder 1/10)
- House on Castle Court Ranch near Ronan, Montana, undated; 72-0492 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Orchard and garden on Castle Court Ranch near Ronan, Montana, undated; 72-0493 (Box-folder 1/10)
- View of Hamilton, Montana, from east side of Bitterroot Valley, Bitterroott Mountains in background, ca. 1910; 72-0494 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Anaconda Company's mill and pond at Hamilton, Montana, in the Bitterroot Valley, ca. 1891-1917; 72-0495 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Main Street in Hamilton, Montana, ca. 1910; 72-0496 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Head of Blodgett Canyon, west of Hamilton, Montana, in the Bitterroot Mountains, ca. 1910; 72-0497 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Rock Creek emerging from Lake Como in the Bitterroot Valley, ca. 1910; 72-0498 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Hamilton, Montana, taken from roof of Ravalli Hotel, undated; 72-0652 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Taft, Montana, undated; 78-0003 (Box-folder 1/10)
- House under construction, no location, undated; 567:1; Note on back: This is a house I worked on last summer. I was foreman on the job in their ....(illegible) (Box-folder 1/10)
- Woman in military uniform, undated; 567:2 (Box-folder 1/10)
- R.J. Maynard, Taft, Montana, 1907; 567:3 (Box-folder 1/10)